Guide to the Stanford Technology Ventures Program, Entrepreneurial Thought Leaders Seminar, Videorecordings SC1209
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Videorecordings, 2001-2014
  - Davis, Geoff, Challenges Faced by Unitus, 2005-10-05; 1380; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Davis talks about one of the biggest challenges he faced with Unitus: coming into an established industry that has been successful and showing that things can be done differently and better.
  - Davis, Geoff, Following Your Gut, 2005-10-05; 1381; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Set your sights high and go for it, says Davis. He encourages students who want to make a difference to believe and follow their dreams with grit and ingenuity.
  - Davis, Geoff, Prodding Small Companies to Think Big, 2005-10-05; 1382; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Davis discusses how Unitus helps transform small non-profit companies into large profitable companies. Unitus makes the companies think bigger and expand their vision. They try to paint the picture of a possibility of a bigger future, he notes.
  - Williams, Evan, Advent of Podcasting, 2005-10-12; 1383; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams, Evan, co-founder of Pyra Labs, creators of Blogger, talks about podcasting and how it started. He believes that due to the "webification" of audio, podcasting has become exciting and popular.
  - Williams, Evan, Future of Podcasting, 2005-10-12; 1384; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams believes that podcasting has just begun and that it is going to grow in the coming years. He explains that people are now only in the 'geocities' phase where they know how to access content but do not know why to do so or do so on an ongoing basis.
  - Williams, Evan, Dealing with Competition, 2005-10-12; 1385; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams gives his views on the evolving competitive landscape in podcasting. He believes that in a new, emerging market, it is about 'growing the pie' and bringing many players into the market to educate the people about the impact and usefulness of the new technology.
  - Williams, Evan, Advice to Aspiring Entrepreneurs, 2005-10-12; 1386; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams advices budding entrepreneurs to start small and think big. You should start with something small and something that you care about, he says. Smaller problems can be solved faster and can be eventually scaled into a big company, he adds.
  - Williams, Evan, Learning from Failure, 2005-10-12; 1387; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams talks about some of his biggest failures and what he learned from them. One of the things he has learned is the importance of building, collaborating and motivating a team.
  - Williams, Evan, Maintaining Focus, 2005-10-12; 1388; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams believes that one of the challenges he faced from very early on was of maintaining focus. He explains that he now has to be more disciplined due to various external diversions.
  - Williams, Evan, Can Entrepreneurship be Taught?, 2005-10-12; 1389; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Williams believes that entrepreneurship can be taught as it is a combination of skills and intense desires that drive a person to overcome challenges.
  - Beaver, Bobby, Passion and Vision, 2006-01-25; 1392; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Entrepreneurs must have passion. Passion and vision are the things entrepreneurs fall back on when their company goes through highs and lows. Bobby Beaver, vice president of technology at Zazzle, explains that the reasons for starting a venture should not be monetary but it should be passion - deep caring for a problem and the drive to solve the problem.
  - Beaver, Bobby, Confidence in Small Teams, 2006-01-25; 1393; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Beaver says that one of the most important lessons he has learned at Zazzle is to have confidence in yourself and your team.
  - Beaver, Bobby, Question Everything, 2006-01-25; 1394; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Beaver tells entrepreneurs to question everything people are telling them to do. Do not accept the status quo, he says. Do not give in to the notion that if it is has been done a certain way, you have to do it the same way, he adds.
  - Beaver, Bobby, Adapt or Die, 2006-01-25; 1395; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Beaver talks about how it is necessary for every company to adapt at every step as it grows, depending on the competitive landscape or technological advances, to make the most of opportunities along the way.
  - Beaver, Bobby, People and Culture of Zazzle, 2006-01-25; 1396; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Beaver believes nothing is more important for a company than the people that comprise it. This is why the Zazzle founders stress culture in their company. They constantly try to infuse values of innovation and empowerment amongst their people. Along with all this, the company also incorporates having fun to make sure their employees are enjoying the ride at Zazzle.
  - Fraser, Janice, Choosing Your Partners, 2006-02-01; 1397; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Fraser, Janice, CEO and a founding partner of Adaptive Path, believes one should choose partners based on who you want to go to when the going gets rough. She talks about the importance of a solid partnership.
  - Fraser, Janice, Coping with Failures, 2006-02-01; 1398; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Fraser believes being an entrepreneur is not a job but a mission. On this journey towards achieveing this mission, you are going to be faced with failures and successes, she says. It is the failures that inform the successes, she adds.
  - Fraser, Janice, Protecting the Culture, 2006-02-01; 1399; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Fraser calls culture the software of her company. She believes it is very important to protect and care for the culture of a company when it is evolving past its nascent stage.
  - Fraser, Janice, Creating Meaning for Employees, 2006-02-01; 1400; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Fraser believes that besides creating meaning for the world, an entrepreneurial venture should be able to create meaning for the people who comprise it as well. In this regard, people are able to passionately and zealously work toward making the company and product successful.
  - Fraser, Janice, Decision-making, 2006-02-01; 1401; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    The efficiency of decision-making is very important to the management of any company. Fraser calls it a kind of 3-legged stool of responsibility, accountability and authority.
  - Fraser, Janice, Alignment and People, 2006-02-01; 1402; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Fraser believes alignment is the underlying principle to everthing we do. The work has to be fulfilling for the people who work in entreprenuerial ventures, she says. It is important to create an environment where people can excel.
  - Fraser, Janice, Managing a Technology-Driven Company, 2006-02-01; 1403; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Fraser discusses her experience as a non-technical person heading a technology driven company. She strongly believes that every manager should be able to lead people who are unlike them to have a successful company.
  - Popovits, Kim, Recruiting a Passionate, All-Star Team, 2006-02-08; 1404; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Popovits, Kim, President and Chief Operating Officer of Genomic Health, talks about how the strength of Genomic Health is its all star team, comprising of A players, who share a common passion of wanting to make a difference. Popovits believes that it is very important to share values and passion with your colleagues to make decision-making in organizations easier.
  - Popovits, Kim, Focusing On Culture, 2006-02-08; 1405; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Popovits talks about the importance of nurturing the culture at an organization. The people and the culture of Genomic Health form the core of the company. It is necessary to stop and celebrate the small and the big successes,she says, and to enjoy what you are doing to keep your company motivated and driven.
  - Bartz, Carol, Tailoring Products for Different Consumer Groups, 2006-03-01; 1406; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Bartz, Carol, chairman of the board, president and CEO of Autodesk, talks about the need to speak with customers to tailor a standard product for different customer groups. She uses the example of AutoCad and the way it has been tailored to specific customers to meet their requirements. She also says that the best way to make a product a standard is to get it to volume.
  - Bartz, Carol, Being Successful in the Global Economy, 2006-03-01; 1407; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Autodesk prices and packages its products differently in different countries. Bartz discusses how Autodesk has been successful doing business in emerging markets. She talks about the importance of looking at wage standards and labor standards of the country when selling global products like AutoCad across the world.
  - Bartz, Carol, Stay Interested, 2006-03-01; 1408; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    According to Bartz, the more interested you are in things around the world, the more interesting you are to somebody else. Make sure your learning curve is always up and to the right, she adds.
  - Bartz, Carol, Making Lemonade: Coping Strategies for Corporate Stresses, 2006-03-01; 1409; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Bartz, Carol, CEO of Autodesk for many years, underlines the silver lining for many stagnating issues in the workplace. Making a plan for yourself is a good idea, but don't let it limit your scope. By bringing value to the organization, you are the one to benefit most. Learning is the most critical aspect of any job; if you're not growing, it's time to uproot. She also points out that bad managers are great teachers, as they are instructive in what not to do when you finally get to fill their role.
  - Bartz, Carol, Pyramids, Not Ladders, 2006-03-01; 1410; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    In this clip, Bartz, Carol points out that young workers needn't be afraid of a lateral career move. Ambition often focuses only on upward motion, whereas well-rounded experience in a number of departments - sales, marketing, or customer service, just to name a few - gives a career a solid foundation. Ladders are unstable, Bartz says, but pyramids have depth, safety, and strength.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Starting out as a Sole Founder, 2006-02-22; 1411; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Goldberg, Michaell, General Partner at Mohr Davidow Ventures and Founder of Axion Inc., discusses his transition from being a venture capitalist to an entrepreneur. He left the venture capital industry to found a company. As a sole founder, he encourages everybody to start a company with at least one co-founder because it entails a difficult and lonely path.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Selling a Venture, 2006-02-22; 1412; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Goldberg talks about the point when he sold the company that he had built for nine years. He goes on to reveal that he would do the same thing then if he knew what he knows today. He says he was happy he sold the company to a bigger company who earned larger revenues on it.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Role of Boards, 2006-02-22; 1413; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Being on the boards of various companies, Goldberg gives his perspective and a sense of the flavor of what happens in board rooms and the roles of different types of boards.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Conflict Between Management Team and Board Members, 2006-02-22; 1414; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Goldberg talks about what happens when there is a conflict between board members and the management team in terms of the direction of the company.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Importance of Patents and Intellectual Property, 2006-02-22; 1415; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Goldberg talks about how understanding the importance of intellectual property, patents, trademarks and copyrights is essential in today's industries.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Career Advice, 2006-02-22; 1416; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Goldberg advices students and young-budding entrepreneurs to follow their passions. You have to be passionate for your company to be able to persist and face the failures that come along the way, he says.
  - Goldberg, Michael, Patenting Genes, 2006-02-22; 1417; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Goldberg gives his views on whether genes should be patented along with an insight into open source biology.
  - Lee, Chong-Moon, Coming to Silicon Valley, 2006-02-15; 1440; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Lee, Chong-Moon, chairman and CEO of Ambex Venture Group, and founder of Diamond Multimedia Systems, talks about his humble beginnings and the frustrations in his family business in Korea that led him to make a journey to Silion Valley.
  - Lee, Chong-Moon, Facing challenges, 2006-02-15; 1441; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Lee reveals how he started his company, the hardships he faced and the persistance that drove him to achieve his goals.
  - Lee, Chong-Moon, Never Give up spirit, 2006-02-15; 1442; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Lee advices entrepreneurs to never give up, fight challenges with perseverance and have a crystal clear vision to be successful.
  - Lee, Chong-Moon, Skills of an entrepreneur, 2006-02-15; 1443; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Lee believes that leadership and dynamic managerial style are two important skills that every successful entrepreneurs must have. He goes on to discuss the necessary skill set that make a successful entrepreneur.
  - Lee, Chong-Moon, Success and Failure, 2006-02-15; 1444; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Lee talks about how winning and losing are parts of everyone's life. However, it is important to learn from each one of them as you go along, he says. The successes and failures that he went through helped him overcome challenges in his business.
  - Lee, Chong-Moon, Change yourself constantly, 2006-02-15; 1445; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    According to Lee, you have to keep changing yourself constantly to be successful. He explains that the more you know the world, the more informed decisions you will be able to make.
  - Liemandt, Joe, Starting a business during undergraduate study, 2005-05-10; 1446; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Liemandt, Joe, founder, CEO and chairman of Trilogy, talks about why entrepreneurship is something everyone needs to do in their career. You will go from the highest highs to the lowest lows in a matter of minutes, he says, but it is the time that is the best and the worst of your life. He advices starting a business when you are an undergraduate student because you do not have a whole lot to lose.
  - Liemandt, Joe, Perseverance: Sticking to your beliefs, 2005-05-10; 1447; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Liemandt talks about how an entrepreneur's beliefs leads to success or failure. As long as you believe in your business, he says, you can persevere. You have to love what you are doing and be passionate about it, he adds.
  - Liemandt, Joe, Guaranteeing Business Value to Customers, 2005-05-10; 1448; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Liemandt talks about how Trilogy moved on from just producing the best enterprise software in the market to adding and guaranteeing business value for its customers.
  - Liemandt, Joe, Sharing Your Passion, 2005-05-10; 1449; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Liemandt discusses how leading a start-up is harder and more stressful than heading a big company. The most difficult thing about being the CEO of a big company is making sure that all the employees share the same vision and passion for the business.
  - Rodan, Katie, Benefits of a Partnership, 2006-04-19; 1450; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Rodan, Katie, co-developer of Proactiv Solution, talks about the benefits of her partnership. She says that it is great for her to have a partner with whom she can share everything and make decisions together to jointly run the business.
  - Rodan, Katie, Discovering and Meeting Market Needs, 2006-04-19; 1451; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Rodan reveals the process of discovering a product that would solve the acne problem that was not being met by any of the products in the market. The main goal was to develop a product that would be easily accessible to target customers.
  - Rodan, Katie, The Value of Effective Market Research, 2006-04-19; 1452; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Rodan, Katie of Proactiv Solutions discusses a personal anecdote with a critical session of market research. The experience sent her team back to the drawing board to revamp a product for adult acne - after revealing that women surveyed didn't think they had acne and didn't care for the product's fragrance. Rodan also discusses her initial resistance to conduct the survey, and the tremendous benefits that it can yield for the entrepreneur.
  - Rodan, Katie, Raising Money and Importance of Licensing Your Product, 2006-04-19; 1453; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Rodan gives an insight into the obstacles faced while raising money for Proactiv. She discusses the importance of licensing a product as a way of raising money for the company.
  - Rodan, Katie, Infomercials - A Way to Reach Your Audience, 2006-04-19; 1454; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Rodan talks about how infomercials were successful in reaching and re-educating the audience on how to solve their skin problems and in turn helped her company realize an unmet need.
  - Rodan, Katie, Owning Your Product Formula, 2006-04-19; 1455; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    During product development, Rodan advices to own the formula of the product, which is an asset, and suggests not to lose ownership of it.
  - Rodan, Katie, Growing the Organization, 2006-04-19; 1456; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Rodan talks about building Proactiv Solutions, getting the right team together and working with a partner to run an organization.
  - Roos, John, Simple Mission Statement, 2006-03-08; 1457; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos, John, chief executive officer of Wilson Sonsini Goodrich & Rosati, recommends having a simple mission statement when thinking about a business. You have to know what you are good at, where your core strengths lie, have a game plan and then stick with it, he says.
  - Roos, John, Focus on Building a Brand, 2006-03-08; 1458; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos says that no matter what kind of industry you get into or the company you start, you should focus on building a brand because that is likely to pay off big time.
  - Roos, John, The Three Circle Strategy, 2006-03-08; 1459; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos shares the Three Circle Strategy used at Wilson Sonsini. He says it is important for all great companies to start out and keep to fairly straightforward strategies yet remain flexible with the moving times.
  - Roos, John, Strengths of Silicon Valley, 2006-03-08; 1460; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos strongly believes that the strength of Silicon Valley lies in the fact that it is built on merit and diversity. Additionally, the Valley is unique in that failure is not considered a stigma, he says.
  - Roos, John, Silicon Valley: An Ecosystem, 2006-03-08; 1461; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos talks about how Silicon Valley is an ecosystem where everyone knows each other and everyone feeds off of each other. It is important when you are starting a company that you want to tap into that ecosystem, he says.
  - Roos, John, Silicon Valley: Changing with the times, 2006-03-08; 1462; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos talks about how the industry in Silicon Valley keeps changing. From the 1970s, the era of the brick and mortar technology industry, the Valley has seen a boom in semiconductor companies and computer companies, followed by the era of information technology and the Internet in the 90s. In this transition, the Valley has become global, he adds.
  - Roos, John, Career Advice: Five Takeaways, 2006-03-08; 1463; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Roos gives five takeaways in his talk: 1) Take risks; 2) Don't be afraid to take a step back in your career if it will help you move forward in the long run; 3) Surround yourself with good people and give them credit; 4) Little things really matter; and 5) Integrity matters more than anything else.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Every Problem is an Opportunity, 2006-04-12; 1464; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig, Tina, Executive Director for the Stanford Technology Ventures Program, believes that every problem is an opportunity for a creative solution. The way you view any problem depends on your attitude.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Value Creation from Opportunities, 2006-04-12; 1465; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig, Tina, Executive Director of the Stanford Technology Ventures Program, walks us through a life-changing hands-on classroom activity where students are taught to identify opportunities in nooks and crannies. With five dollars in seed funding and two hours of execution, she reports on the success of the exercise, and that many students reaped over one hundred times the initial investment (and others built a business without using any funding at all). Look for problems around you, says Seelig, and convert them into opportunities that create value. Embrace the opportunity to challenge assumptions and identify true cultural, social, or technological need.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Luck and Success, 2006-04-12; 1466; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    The harder I work, the luckier I get, says Seelig. Get out there and put yourself in a position to make yourself lucky, she adds.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, "Career Advice: Interests, Skills and Market", 2006-04-12; 1467; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig says that it is best to find the intersection between your passion, your skills, and the market. Passion is necessary, but passion alone is not sufficient to pursue a career, she adds.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Risk-taking and Failure, 2006-04-12; 1468; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    According to Seelig, if you are not failing sometimes, then you are not taking enough risks. Silicon Valley supports a culture of risk taking and embraces failure. She encourages everyone to take risks and not to get daunted by the fear of failure.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Learning from Failure, 2006-04-12; 1469; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig often makes her students write failure resumes as a way to recognize the mistakes that they have made as well as the lessons they have learned from those mistakes.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Career Advice: Don't Wait to be Anointed, 2006-04-12; 1470; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig advices that just as entrepreneurs empower themselves, you too should not wait for someone to tell you that you are empowered to take on a new responsibility. Just do it, she adds.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Importance of Networking, 2006-04-12; 1471; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig believes that it is important to build relationships and network with the people you meet everyday. It is a small world and as you go through life you are going to meet the same people again and again, she adds.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Balancing Priorities, 2006-04-12; 1472; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig talks about the importance of figuring out and balancing priorities. She believes it is necessary to reassess your priorities frequently, selecting a few things to focus on.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Working in Teams, 2006-04-12; 1473; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Seelig believes that while working in a team it is important to make everyone else on your team successful.
  - Seelig, Tina Lynn, Be Fabulous!, 2006-04-12; 1474; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    According to Seelig, never miss an opportunity to be fabulous! She encourages everyone to embrace this idea and to help make the world a better place.
  - Marrone, Pam, The Founding of AgraQuest, 2006-05-10; 1478; 1 computer file(s) (mp4)
    Marrone, Pam, founder and former Chairman/CEO of AgraQuest Inc., talks about how she turned her childhood passion and love for bugs into a lifelong commitment that led her to found AgraQuest.